Hello
[music]
friends, who doesn't like reports and discounts?
Whenever we go to purchase something new,
we definitely try cashback reports and
discounts. NC, that is,
No Claim Bonus, is also a similar
report which the health insurance company
gives to those who do not make a claim.
Now, how many types of No Claim Bonus are there, how much
discount do you get,
for how many years will you get this benefit,
and some important things which are
very important for your knowledge, you will know all this in this video.
Hello friends, my name is Ravinder
Singh and I welcome you
to the YouTube channel of DSC Solutions.
Understanding insurance is very easy. If
you like the information seen here, if you
find it useful for some, then
you can also subscribe to the channel
and definitely share and like the video. Let's
start the video. Friends,
what is the definition of health insurance mediclaim?
See, whenever you enter into
your health insurance for the treatment of any of your diseases, it is
considered a plate and if you do not make a claim in any year, then it is
considered a glacier.  In
return, insurance companies pass you some
benefits, which is called no claim
bonus. You will get this no claim bonus on
every claim. There are
two types of benefits that can be passed. The
first is discount on
premium, which means
you are
given some discount on the premium paid every year in April because you did
not make any claim in the previous year, due to which your
annual premium
reduces a little. Now,
if you continue to get this benefit for several years, then
you can get a maximum
premium waiver of up to 50%
in the form of NCP. Friends, in another way,
you also get it in this way, that is, your sum insured, that is, the
sum insured that you get,
that amount is increased
after every claim. Let us
understand this by an example. Suppose your policy has a
time limit of Rs 5 lakh and
you have not made any claim in the next year and the
no claim bonus in your policy is ten
percent, that is, ₹5  10 times send 50
thousand rupees by squeezing your time, the limit will
increase further, now it will not remain 5 lakhs but it will become
5.5 lakh rupees, in the same way you keep
increasing your limit every year
for the same premium, you do
not have to pay a lot of money for this, now this maximum can be
increased by 50% or even up to 100%,
this limit is mentioned in your insurance policy
document, friends
now let us know three
important points about it, the first point is
that no claim bonus is transferable, that is, if
you have collected a lot of no claim bonus by staying in a company for
four-five years without making any claim,
and after that if
you want to change your insurance company, then you
can transfer this no claim bonus along with it there,
and in that insurance company also, your
quality time squeeze, that is, time leave
plus no claim bonus, you will start from there, if you
understand by example, then Malviya has collected
₹5 time leave and ₹3 as your no claim
bonus and after that you can change your insurance
company  If you want to change, then you will
leave your job in a new company and take ₹5000,
even if you love the same, you will get a no claim bonus of
₹3 from your first day there, you will get
its benefit, so you can transfer the no claim bonus.
Point number two,
not every insurance company provides NCB, you will find it mentioned
in your policy document
or
you can also ask your insurance consultant, if any
insurance company
mentions the NCB, then definitely read it, how much will you get every year
and up to what maximum limit you can
collect your NCB, you must
check this, friends, the third and last point comes,
because due to no claim bonus
you can double your sum insured
and also reduce your premium by half,
so this is a very important thing, do not
waste your time unnecessarily behind some small gland, do
not forcefully take a claim so that at the time of any big emergency
you get a lot of time
and you will not have to exceed the limit by leaving this time
and here you also save the premium for many
years  So friends, now that you have
understood all this well,
you will be able to use every benefit of it and
you will not have any problem in understanding it
and friends, whatever ₹1 of insurance premium you pay
to the insurance company,
it has a lot of value and you should make full
use of it with the right information, so
friends, see you next week with more important updates and
important information, stay fit
and take care, stay fit and stay healthy,
thank you
[Music]